Guide to the Laurence MacDaniels papers, [ca. 1915]-1986.
Laurence MacDaniels papers,
- Pollination - Horticultural Society Meeting, Date Unknown (Box 17, Folder 17)
  data and graph
- [envelope] Pollination Data Spring 1929 Home Copy, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  data
- Mouse and Winter Injury Survey, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  Also Records of Bridge Grafting and Inarching Spring 1930; field notes
- Winter Injury Records C.U. Orchards Research Spring 1934, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  field notes
- Banana Study, Date Unknown (Box 17, Folder 21)
  drawings
- Data on Bending Pears and Apples, Date Unknown (Box 17, Folder 22)
- Miscellaneous Notes 1928, 1928 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  notes on fruit buds
- Research Notes - Crotch Studies, Date Unknown (Box 17, Folder 24)
  drawings and field notes
- Soil Treatment - Blueberry Outline, Date Unknown (Box 17, Folder 25)
  notes
- Research Notes - Graft Union, Date Unknown (Box 17, Folder 26)
  1 sheet of paper headed: "Collect Material"
- Made at Cleveland Meetings, Size of Vascular Elements in Kieffer Pear Trees Making Norman Growth and in Those Invigorated by Pruning. Samples Taken From Outer Annual Ring., Date Unknown (Box 17, Folder 27)
  data sheets
- L. H. MacDaniels Apple Pollination Bibliography, Date Unknown (Box 17, Folder 28)
- Pollination Results with McIntosh Spring 1928, 1928 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  data sheets, notes
- Pollination Results in Champlain Valley 1930, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 30)
- Yield Record Blanks - Skutt Orchard M157, Date Unknown (Box 17, Folder 31)
- Pollination - Temperature Charts Etc. 1931, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 32)
- Pollen Germination Tests 1932-33 Cowart, 1932-1933 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  data sheets and notes
- Possibilities of Hand Pollination, Date Unknown (Box 17, Folder 34)
  notes and data sheets
- Pollen Germination Studies 1929 -, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 35)
- Pollen Germination 1931 Et. Seq. (1932), 1931-1932 (Box 17, Folder 36)
- Lily Pollination Miscellaneous Notes, Date Unknown (Box 17, Folder 37)
- [envelope] Pollination Data 1932 Seed Count and Weight of Fruits, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 38)
- Pollination Data 1929 Pears, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 39)
- Nut Correspondence 1925-26, 1925-1926 (Box 17, Folder 40)
  including W. G. Bixby, W. H. Chandler, C. A. Reed, etc.
- Loose Letters 1937, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 41)
  to A. B. Burrell, from E. C. Auchter
- Lilies Correspondence to July 1937, 1937-07 (Box 17, Folder 42)
  includes John Sheepers, B. Y. Morrison, G. L. Slate, etC.
- Bishop Museum Research on the Banana (Musa Fehi) From July 1, 1938-June 30, 1939, 1938-07-01-1939-06-30 (Box 17, Folder 43)
- Loose Correspondence 1939, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 44)
  regarding apples
- Nut Letters and Information of General Interest Permanent File 1935-38, 1935-1938 (Box 17, Folder 45)
- Lilies - Chairman Lily Committee, Date Unknown (Box 17, Folder 46)
  correspondence including S. M. Emsweller, Mrs. Mortimer J. Fox, E. P. Imle, B. Y. Morrison, G. L. Slate, A. B. Stout
- Personal, Lilies July 1, 1938-June 30, 1939, 1938-07-01-1939-06-30 (Box 17, Folder 47)
  correspondence including Phillipe Brierley, S. L. Emsweller, B. Y. Morrison, G. L. Slate, H. B. Tukey
- Bishop Museum From July 1, 1939 to June 30, 1940, 1939-07-01-1940-06-30 (Box 17, Folder 48)
  includes correspondence with C. A. Reed, G. L. Slate, E. L. Overholser, envelope with photos and some negatives of Apple Crotch Research, note from L. H. Bailey to LHM attached to correspondence - regarding Bishop museum manuscript 1939
- Nut Orchards - Maps and Labels (1930-1935), 1930-1935 (Box 17, Folder 49)
- Nut Tree Plantings, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 50)
  Mimeographed Material Prepared for the Northern Nut Growers Association in Fall 1931
- Nut Cracking Records - 1932-33, 1932-1933 (Box 17, Folder 51)
- Nut Collection, 1912 (Box 17, Folder 52)
  "Checklist of Morris Collection of Edible Nuts of the World Represented in Cases in Department of Horticulture, Cornell, University 1912"
- Nut Contest - Correspondence Dealing With Prize Winning Hickory and Walnuts and Scions Requested 1934-5, 1934-1935 (Box 17, Folder 53)
  Correspondence Dealing With Prize Winning Hickory and Walnuts and Scions Requested 1934-5
- Nut Letters Not Related to Contest - 9 Extension, Etc., 1934-1935 (Box 17, Folder 54)
  Regarding Good Nuts Not in Contest 1934-5
- Nut Contest - Letters Which Have Required Special Answers 1934-5, 1934-1935 (Box 17, Folder 55)
- Northern Nut Growers Association Correspondence 1933, 1933 (Box 17, Folder 56)
- Nut Contest - Letters Making Inquiry Regarding Contest But Not Relating to Samples 1934, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 57)
- Nut Contest - Correspondence Dealing With Hickory Nuts Given Rating of M But Later Discarded 1934-5, 1934-1935 (Box 17, Folder 58)
- Nut Contest, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 59)
  Unanswered Letters Concerning Walnuts - Discarded - Superior Nuts - 9a - Not Superior - 9b - 9c Not Tested 1934
- Nut Contest 9, 1934-07-01-1935-06-30 (Box 17, Folder 60)
  Unanswered Letters Concerning Hickory Nuts Discarded (Few Letters Concerning Both Hickory and Walnuts) July 1, 1934-June 30, 1935; 9 - rules sent
- Nut Grafting Spring 1935 - Check Up, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 61)
  includes manuscripts "Some Experiences in Nut Tree Grafting at Ithaca, NY" - LHM, "Some Experiences with Nut Tree Grafting at Ithaca" LHM (different manuscript.), "Northern Nut Growers' Association Report of Committee on Varieties and Judging Standards," field notes
- Nut Varieties - For Standard Plant Names, Date Unknown (Box 17, Folder 62)
  correspondence with C. A. Reed et al - regarding nut varieties
- [envelope] Envelope of Apple Crotch Study Photos; Pamphlets on Nut Growing, Date Unknown (Box 17, Folder 63)
- Northern Nut Growers Association Research 1973-1974 Filbert Project Warren Johnson - Joe Saunders, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  notes and correspondence with W. Johnson
- Northern Nut Growers Association Manuscript Figures for Pruning Paper 1973, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  photos and brochure on pruning from North Central Forest Experiment Station
- Miscellaneous Material 1978-79 and 1968-70, 1968-1979 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  includes nut culture information, Oberlin College material, extension bulletins, miscellaneous correspondence
- [envelope] Nuts in Landscape Oct. 1969 Stiffels Article also Nuts Photographs, 1969-10 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Plantations - Trees in Trouble - Active manuscript June 1972, 1972-06 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  notes and original manuscript
- Bulletin 701 Revision 1969, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  copy of Cornell Extension Bulletin 701 - Nut Growing in New York State (LHM) and envelope with figures for publication
- Miscellaneous Nut Tree Material 1968, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  some correspondence, reprints, some general conservation material
- Miscellaneous Nut Tree Material, Date Unknown (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Northern Nut Growers Association 1971-72 Correspondence - General, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Northern Nut Growers Association Nut Growers 1966-67-68, 1966-1968 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  newsletters, price lists, correspondence, etc.
- Miscellaneous Nut Culture 1975, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  mostly general correspondence
- Tompkins County Environmental Management Council 1975-76, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  miscellaneous material - meeting notes and minutes
- Black Walnut Culture - Leaflets, Etc., Date Unknown (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous Current 1975-76, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  correspondence with P. F. Tear of Oberlin, New York State Electric and Gas, copy of "Here We Are, Where Do We Go From Here?" material regarding Shade Tree Advisory Committee, Nature Conservancy, etc.
- Northern Nut Growers Association 1973 Nut Samples for Dr. Lisk Analysis, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous Material 1973, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  working copy and 1 of manuscript "Fundamentals of Tree Pruning with Special Reference to the Black Walnut (LHM 1973). copy of Evaluation of Black Walnut Samples Committee Report (1973), general nut material, miscellany
- Miscellaneous Nut Material 1970-73, 1970-1973 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  Correspondence - regarding general nut culture, judging schedules, pamphlets, etc.
- Nut Article for Horticulture Stiffek - Miscellaneous Correspondence References 1964-65, 1964-1965 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  includes copy of manuscript "Nut Trees for Gardeners (LHM 1965)
- Northern Nut Growers Association Ames Meeting 1972, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  correspondence, information, brochures, etc. regarding Ames meeting
- Northern Nut Growers Association Testing 1972 Crop Data, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  See Also Cards, Some Plantation Data
- Miscellaneous Nut Culture, Date Unknown (Box 18, Folder 21)
  mainly pamphlets, etc.
- Northern Nut Growers Association Horticultural Manuscript - March 1974 Stiffek manuscript All About Nuts, 1974-03 (Box 18, Folder 22)
- Northern Nut Growers Association Lancaster 1973, 1970-1973 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  contains miscellaneous material regarding black walnut judging, some regarding Lancaster meeting, correspondence with Spencer Chase (1970), George Slate (1970), notes about Lancaster 1973, etc.
- Men's Garden Club 1973-74 National Material and Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 24)
- General Nut Culture et al, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  includes notes on "The Black Walnut Situation Dec. 1, 1972" (LHM)
- Northern Nut Growers Association 1975 Butternuts Ashworth (1973-78), 1973-1978 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  judging schedules, miscellaneous material, correspondence - regarding general nut culture, etc.
- To Answer Fall 1976-1977, 1976-1977 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  miscellaneous material and correspondence
- Tree Crops 1975, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  miscellaneous tree crops material and correspondence
- Plantations - Nut Collection, Date Unknown (Box 18, Folder 29)
- Northern Nut Growers Association 1970-71 Walnut Testing Other Than Thomas - Also Hickory - Elmer Myers - To Test 1971 If Possible, 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  black walnut variety reports
- Nut Growers - 1964, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  agenda for 1965 Board meetings, miscellaneous material, correspondence
- Nut Growers Convention in September(?) 1963, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  pamphlets from meeting with notes on back
- Northern Nut Growers Association Miscellaneous Material, Date Unknown (Box 18, Folder 33)
  correspondence, notes, etc.
- Northern Nut Growers Association Manuscript 1966, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  "The Present Status of Research with Hardy Nut Trees," notes, etc.
- Walnuts - Mr. Serr of California, Date Unknown (Box 18, Folder 35)
- Slate - Talk on Nuts to Connecticut Nut Growers 1971, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  correspondence with Slate and mimeographed copy of GL's notes for talk
- Northern Nut Growers Association 1970-71 - Miscellaneous Material - Also Other Florida Letters, 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 37)
- Northern Nut Growers Association Walnut Testing - Current Test 1971-72 Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  includes correspondence with Ashworth
- Northern Nut Growers Association 1970-71 Miscellaneous Letters - Jaynes, Chase, 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 39)
- Miscellaneous Material 1973-78, 1973-1978 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  scoring cards for black walnut testing, chestnut material, Northern Nut Growers Association correspondence, Oberlin correspondence, etc.
- [envelope] McGraw Encyclopedia - Nut Articles, Correspondence, Date Unknown (Box 18, Folder 41)
- [envelope] McGraw Hill Encyclopedia Second Copies, Date Unknown (Box 18, Folder 42)
- Northern Nut Growers Association Judging Standards Committee Reports 1937, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 43)
- Nut Data Black Walnut 1938-39, 1938-1939 (Box 18, Folder 44)
- Nut Tree Scions Other Than From New York State Contest Spring 1935, 1935 (Box 18, Folder 45)
  correspondence including G. L. Slate, C. A. Reed, etc.
- Nuts 1934-35, 1934-1935 (Box 18, Folder 46)
  correspondence including C. A. Reed, G. L. Slate, notes, etc.
- Nut Contest Records 1934-35, 1934-1935 (Box 18, Folder 47)
  data, notes, etc.
- Nut Growing - Matters of Current Importance 1936, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 48)
  correspondence including C. A. Reed, notes, data, etc.
- Letters Dealing with Nut Growing Permanent File - Miscellaneous Nut Information 1924-1935, 1924-1935 (Box 18, Folder 49)
  includes correspondence with C. A. Reed, W. G. Bixby, etc.
- L. H. MacDaniels Personal File 1918-1920, 1918-1920 (Box 18, Folder 50)
  personal correspondence between LHM and FCM, application for FCM for France visa 1919, correspondence between LHM and E.C. Cochran (FCM father) 1918-20, W. H. Chandler, correspondence from Derindje, Asia Minor 1918-20
- Nut Correspondence 1922, 1922 (Box 18, Folder 51)
- Personal Letters 1923-24, 1923-1924 (Box 18, Folder 52)
- Nomenclature 1923-24, 1923-1924 (Box 18, Folder 53)
  correspondence regarding nomenclature, mostly with H. P. Gould of USDA
- Nut Correspondence 1923-24, 1923-1924 (Box 18, Folder 54)
  includes H. B. Tukey, W. Bixby, A. J. Heinicke, Northern Nut Growers Association
- Nut Correspondence 1924-25, 1924-1925 (Box 18, Folder 55)
  includes NNGA, C. A. Reed, etc.
- Sabbatic Leave 13 1925-26, 1925-1926 (Box 18, Folder 56)
  W. H. Chandler. etc.
- Nut-Grass Data - Palmquist and MacDaniels 1958, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  data sheets and field notes and blank data sheets
- Horticultural Handbook - Current Manuscript Climate 1958 Handbook - Philippine Agriculture Send Home, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  misc. notes and observations, notes and outlines and drafts for handbook
- L. H. MacDaniels - Letters Not Filed 1964-66 (mostly 1965), 1964-1966 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  correspondence with various individuals regarding different horticultural matters - i.e. - annuals, lilies, standardization of plant names, general nut culture, etc.
- Miscellaneous Letters Not Filed 1964-65, 1964-1965 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  correspondence with various individuals different horticultural matters especially nut culture, draft of "Hazelnuts and Filberts," reference to 3 month assignment in Mexico with regard to lily culture and judging standards, reference to walnut toxicity (C. Davis) and other horticultural matters, letter from G. L. Slate
- Biological Sciences - Reorganization 1964, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  1 copy each 3 reports: "Comments on the Report of the President's Committee on Biological Sciences" by the Department of Entomology and Limnology [Cornell University], "The College of Agriculture Committee for the Study of The Corson Comittee Report" (1964), "Report of the President's Committee on Biological Sciences" March 4, 1964 with cover letter to J. A. Perkins, President Cornell University
- Biology Evaluation 1963, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  includes correspondence with C. E. Palm, dean of College of Agriculture, copy of report: "Biology at Cornell - Report of the Special Comittee Appointed by the President of the University (1963) with notes by LHM
- Miss Garrett - Necrology 1964-65, 1964-1965 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  includes correspondence with President Perkins regarding faculty necrology with special reference to Clara Louise Garrett, copy of manuscript: "Statement for Faculty Necrology Clara Louise Garrett - Feb. 16, 1882-Aug. 14, 1964" by LHM, R. J. Lambert, E. L. Burckmyer, and copy of 1st draft with margin notes, other notes and correspondende - regarding C. L. Garrett
- Garden Information Center - Misc. Letters 1964, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Lilies - Acquisitions and Dispersements (1964), 1964 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  correspondence regarding lily culture
- Lilies - Miscellaneous Lily Society Material 1964, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  correspondence
- Lilies - General Extension Inquiry 1964, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Nut Letters - Miscellaneous Extension 1959 + 1964-65, 1959-1965 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Patzcuaro Project Baty and Miscellaneous 1964, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  statement of project and correspondence
- Personal L. H. MacDaniels 1964, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  miscellaneous correspondence including E. M. Hildebrand
- Plantations Letters 1963, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 15)
- Plantations - Minutes, Agenda, General 1964, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 16)
- No folder 17 (Box 19, Folder 17)
- Cornell Plantations - 1964, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  correspondence and meeting minutes
- Cornell Plantations - Publicity and Promotion, Date Unknown (Box 19, Folder 19)
  pamphlets, etc.
- Cornell Plantations 1963 - Budget - Miscellaneous Reports, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 20)
- Cornell Plantations 1963 - Correspondence and Memos, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 21)
- Cornell Plantations - 1962 Active, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  meeting minutes and correspondence, etc.
- Official Unanswered Letters 1957-58, 1957-1958 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  miscellaneous correspondence regarding general horticulture
- Correspondence - Answered But Not Filed 1957-9, 1957-1959 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  Regarding horticultural matters, personal correspondence with Everett MacDaniels et al, Cornell University Plantations material, reference to Arnold Arboretum suit, correspondence with G. L. Slate, J. G. Seeley, G.M.H. Lawrence, E. F. Savage, etc.
- Branch Abscission - Manuscript, Date Unknown (Box 19, Folder 25)
  data sheets, 1st drafts, notes
- Branch Abscission - Drawings, Date Unknown (Box 19, Folder 26)
  includes photos and negatives
- Branch Abscission - Manuscript, Date Unknown (Box 19, Folder 27)
  notes, drawings and data sheets
- Branch Abscission Notes 1956, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 28)
- Branch Abscission Old Material, Date Unknown (Box 19, Folder 29)
  page proof - first draft, notes
- Branch Abscission - Old Notes 1945, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 30)
- Abscission - Text Figures, Date Unknown (Box 19, Folder 31)
- Walnut Broom Disease - Correspondence 1962-64, 1962-1964 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  notes and correspondence
- L. H. MacDaniels Walnut Bunch Disease 1963-64, 1963-1964 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  correspondence and copy with margin notes; "Walnut Bunch Disease Problem" LHM and D. S. Walsh
- Chestnut Letters - Blight - Stock Scion 1964, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 34)
- Canton Island Project - Degener 1964, 1964-12 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  correspondence and map
- Canton Island Report 1950-51, 1950-1951 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  copy report: Board of Water Supply - City of Honolulu Chemical Laboratory Report for LHM, maps, field notes, data sheets, soil profile, manila envelope containing more data
- Frost Studies - Correspondence Records 1964, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 37)
- Nut Nurseries - [1951-52], 1951-1952 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  many copies of list of nut nurseries in United States
- Trees 1965, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  copy of: "Small Trees for the Home Grounds," R. G. Mower, "Street Trees for Residential Areas," A. S. Liebeman and R. G. Mower, "Ecology and Environment," R. G. Mower
- Plantations - Hickory Planting, Date Unknown (Box 19, Folder 40)
- Seed Nuts for Plantations 1964, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 41)
- Black Walnut Toxicity, Date Unknown (Box 19, Folder 42)
  reprint: Injurious Influence of Bark of Black Walnut Root on Seedlings of Tomato and Alfalfa, Babette I. Brown, Cornell University; copy of Black Walnut Toxicity, LHM
- Miscellaneous - Plate - Nuts - Lilies 1956-58, 1956-1958 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  correspondence with James B. Plate regarding Hartmann and Kester manuscript with copy of manuscript, etc.
- Unmarked photo, Date Unknown (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Fruit Trees - Patzcuaro Mexico, Date Unknown (Box 20, Folder 2)
  photos and negatives
- Lily Project 1971 Compost Pile, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  negatives and prints
- Miscellaneous Loose Photos and Negatives, Date Unknown (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Negatives - Nut Trees, Frost on Cucurbits, Date Unknown (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Negatives and Photos Compost Pile, Date Unknown (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Photos and Negs - Palms-New Caledonia, Lily Family - Backhouse Hybrid, Date Unknown (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Negs and Photos 422 Chestnut St., Date Unknown (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Origin of Flower Buds in Lanzone - Philippines, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  outline and abstract with notes 1958
- Writing - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, Date Unknown (Box 20, Folder 10)
  "How Can the University Make Better Use of Its Retired Professors?" (LHM, " A Plea For Small Glens" (LHM)
- Glen Devastation - Cayuga Glen Project, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  correspondence with Gordon Cummings 1965
- Philippine Project - Correspondence Cornell University, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  Seeley, Pridham, Anderson, Dimock, Sweet, Naegele, et a1 1957
- Personal - Unanswered Correspondence 1957-59, 1957-1959 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  includes brother Everett, members of department, etc.
- Philippine Project - Current Folder Miscellaneous Guise 1957, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 14)
- Philippines - Personal Correspondence - Mostly Family Other Than Cornell Not Related to Project 1958, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 15)
- Correspondence for L. H. MacDaniels 1956-1957, 1956-1957 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  miscellaneous correspondence including fire hazard in Roberts Hall (1957), miscellaneous horticultural matters, post-retirement matters both official and personal, general nut culture (chestnut and walnut), discussion of language requirement for Dr. DeFree, lily material, LHM bibliography, E. F. Palmer
- L. H. MacDaniels - Floriculture I Lecture Notes Folder 1, 1952-1955 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  Introduction-Structure-Function 1952-1955
- L. H. MacDaniels - Floriculture Course I Lecture Notes Folder 3, 1951-1953 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  Beginning Soils 1951-53
- L. H. MacDaniels Lecture Notes Floriculture I Folder 2, 1953-1954 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  Light, Temperature, Water 1953-54
- L. H. MacDaniels Bailey Hortorium - Hal Moore, G. H. M. Lawrence 1958, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  correspondence regarding Bailey Hortorium with G. H. M. Lawrence, Director of Bailey Hortorium, E. M. Palmquist, etc.
- Yugoslavia - Official and Personal #1 Plants and Scions - Serr, Hyland-Fisher, Slate, Scott, McGraw 1962, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  correspondence and some notes
- Personal 1964-65, 1964-1965 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  personal correspondence with various individuals regarding horticultural as well as other matters, includes G.H.M. Lawrence, G. Slate, and some fluoridation reference
- Plantations - Long Range Plans 1964-66, 1964-1966 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  correspondence, meeting minutes, agenda, notes, reports about future of Plantations and projects
- Answered Not Filed 1965, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  miscellaneous correspondence regarding various horticultural matters
- George H. Rockwell - Personal and Plantations 1965, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 25)
- American Society for Horticultural Science Caribbean Section 1965, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  correspondence and information regarding annual meetings in El Salvador and Jamaica
- To Be Answered Dec. 1964, 1964-1965 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  miscellaneous correspondence all dated 1965
- Letters - Current Jan-Feb 1966 Not Filed Needing Attention, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  miscellaneous correspondence
- Fluoridation, 1964 (Box 21)
  Signed petitions opposing the proposed fluoridation of the Ithaca water supply (1964).
- "The Family Record - Cochran - Allen commenced by W. C. Cocheran Jan. 1st 1882., Date Unknown (Box 21)
  Xeroxed copies
- "The Hospice Idea a Self Interview by L. H. MacDaniels March 1982", Date Unknown (Box 21)
  Manuscript recorded, transcribed and edited by Damon Boynton.
- Miscellaneous 1975, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  includes correspondence with G. L. Slate, F. M. Abbey of North American Lily Society, Spencer Chase with news of G. Slate illness, miscellaneous "appeals" literature, some personal correspondence (Keyes Metcalf, Ken Spears)
- Miscellaneous 1967, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  apple literature, plant science bulletin, miscellaneous correspondence (1967), N. W. Stuart, G. P. Coleman, G. Slate, G. Lawrence, and other miscellaneous correspondence